Contact

tchild2@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/tarachilders-5a921313a (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Advanced Cardiac Life Support (ACLS)

Basic Life Support (BLS)
CCRN

Honors-Awards

Honorable Mention for Unit of Distinction

Tara Childers

BSN, RN, CCRN

Mobile, Alabama Area

Summary

Experienced Cardiovascular Intensive Care Nurse with a demonstrated history of working in the hospital & health care industry. Skilled in Advanced Cardiac Life Support (ACLS), Team Building, Critical Care Nursing, Employee Training, and Customer Experience. Strong healthcare services professional with a Bachelor of Science (B.S.) focused in BSN from Jacksonville University.

Experience

Providence Hospital CVICU RN November 2019 - Present (8 months) Mobile, Alabama Area

HCA Healthcare 16 years 6 months

Director of Med/Surge/Oncology January 2018 - October 2019 (1 year 10 months) Orange Park, Florida

Clinical Nurse Manager CVICU & MSICU October 2016 - January 2018 (1 year 4 months)

RN, CVICU August 2013 - October 2016 (3 years 3 months) Orange Park, Florida

Nursing care for general CV population including open heart recovery, lung and vascular. Also cared for MSICU and TICU population when needed; TNCC and CCRN certified; proficient in hemodynamic monitoring and adjusting, vasoactive drip titration, vent management and weaning, CRRT, IABP, Impella, EKOS.

RN, CVICU & TICU August 2009 - August 2013 (4 years 1 month) Pensacola, Florida RN, Charge Nurse, PCU

August 2004 - August 2009 (5 years 1 month)

West Florida Hospital, Pensacola, Fl

Care for ICU, CVICU, & TICU stepdown population; CN duties; Rounding with CVS daily

Nurse Intern

May 2003 - August 2004 (1 year 4 months)

West Florida Hospital, Pensacola, Fl

Dynamic clinical assist role on float team

Select Specialty Hospital

Staff RN

September 2008 - September 2009 (1 year 1 month)

Pensacola, Florida

Care for patients requiring long term acute care; long term vent management/ weaning, extensive wound care, wound vacs, IV abx therapy

Cardiology Consultants

Registered Medical Assistant

March 2000 - May 2003 (3 years 3 months)

Pensacola, Florida

Patient preparation for MD visits by obtaining weights, vital signs, medication history and clarification, 12 lead EKG, assisting with examinations, suture removal, obtaining medical records, scheduling tests and providing education, phlebotomy.

Education

Jacksonville University

Bachelor of Science (B.S.), BSN · (2018 - 2019)

Pensacola State College

Associate of Arts (A.A.), Pre-Pharmacy Studies · (2010 - 2011)

Pensacola State College

Associate of Science (AS), Registered Nursing/Registered

Nurse · (2002 - 2004)

Saint Johns River State College

Associate of Arts - AA